<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

     <string name="tip1">
         <b>1.LOSING WEIGHT</b> - Losing weight reduces the risk of diabetes. People in one large study reduced their risk of developing diabetes by almost 60% after losing approximately 7% of their body weight with changes in exercise and diet.
          The American Diabetes Association recommends that people with prediabetes lose at least 7% to 10% of their body weight to prevent disease progression. More weight loss will translate into even greater benefits.
          Set a weight-loss goal based on your current body weight. Talk to your doctor about reasonable short-term goals and expectations, such as a losing 1 to 2 pounds a week.
     </string>
    <string name="tip2">
        <b>2. BE MORE PHYSICALLY ACTIVE</b> - There are many benefits to regular physical activity. Exercise can help you:

Lose weight
Lower your blood sugar
Boost your sensitivity to insulin — which helps keep your blood sugar within a normal range
Goals for most adults to promote weight loss and maintain a healthy weight include:

Aerobic exercise. Aim for 30 minutes or more of moderate to vigorous aerobic exercise — such as brisk walking, swimming, biking or running — on most days for a total of at least 150 minutes a week.
Resistance exercise. Resistance exercise — at least 2 to 3 times a week — increases your strength, balance and ability to maintain an active life. Resistance training includes weightlifting, yoga and calisthenics.
Limited inactivity. Breaking up long bouts of inactivity, such as sitting at the computer, can help control blood sugar levels. Take a few minutes to stand, walk around or do some light activity every 30 minutes.
     </string>

    <string name="tip3">
        <b>3. EAT HEALTHY PLANT FOOD</b> - Plants provide vitamins, minerals and carbohydrates in your diet. Carbohydrates include sugars and starches — the energy sources for your body — and fiber. Dietary fiber, also known as roughage or bulk, is the part of plant foods your body can\t digest or absorb.

Fiber-rich foods promote weight loss and lower the risk of diabetes. Eat a variety of healthy, fiber-rich foods, which include:
<ul>
Fruits such as tomatoes, peppers and fruit from trees
Non starchy vegetables, such as leafy greens, broccoli and cauliflower
Legumes, such as beans, chickpeas and lentils
Whole grains, such as whole-wheat pasta and bread, whole-grain rice, whole oats, and quinoa
The benefits of fiber include:
</ul>
Slowing the absorption of sugars and lowering blood sugar levels
Interfering with the absorption of dietary fat and cholesterol
Managing other risk factors that affect heart health, such as blood pressure and inflammation
Helping you eat less because fiber-rich foods are more filling and energy rich
     </string>

    <string name="tip4">
        <b>4. EAT HEALTHY FATS</b> - Fatty foods are high in calories and should be eaten in moderation. To help lose and manage weight, your diet should include a variety of foods with unsaturated fats, sometimes called "good fats."

Unsaturated fats — both monounsaturated and polyunsaturated fats — promote healthy blood cholesterol levels and good heart and vascular health. Sources of good fats include:

Olive, sunflower, safflower, cottonseed and canola oils
Nuts and seeds, such as almonds, peanuts, flaxseed and pumpkin seeds
Fatty fish, such as salmon, mackerel, sardines, tuna and cod
Saturated fats, the "bad fats," are found in dairy products and meats. These should be a small part of your diet. You can limit saturated fats by eating low-fat dairy products and lean chicken and pork.
    </string>

    <string name="tip5">
        <b>5. SKIP FAD DIETS AND MAKE HEALTHIER CHOICES</b> - Many fad diets — such as the glycemic index, paleo or keto diets — may help you lose weight. There is little research, however, about the long-term benefits of these diets or their benefit in preventing diabetes.

Your dietary goal should be to lose weight and then maintain a healthier weight moving forward. Healthy dietary decisions, therefore, need to include a strategy that you can maintain as a lifelong habit. Making healthy decisions that reflect some of your own preferences for food and traditions may be beneficial for you over time.

One simple strategy to help you make good food choices and eat appropriate portions sizes is to divide up your plate. These three divisions on your plate promote healthy eating:

One-half: fruit and nonstarchy vegetables
One-quarter: whole grains
One-quarter: protein-rich foods, such as legumes, fish or lean meats

    </string>

    <string name="tip6">
        <b>1.DO NOT SMOKE OR USE TOBACCO</b> - One of the best things you can do for your heart is to stop smoking or using smokeless tobacco. Even if you\re not a smoker, be sure to avoid secondhand smoke.

Chemicals in tobacco can damage the heart and blood vessels. Cigarette smoke reduces the oxygen in the blood, which increases blood pressure and heart rate because the heart has to work harder to supply enough oxygen to the body and brain.

There\s good news though. The risk of heart disease starts to drop in as little as a day after quitting. After a year without cigarettes, the risk of heart disease drops to about half that of a smoker. No matter how long or how much you smoked, you\ll start reaping rewards as soon as you quit.
    </string>
    <string name="tip7">
        <b>2.GET MOVING: AIM FOR AT LEAST 30 TO 60 MINUTES OF ACTIVITY DAILY</b> - Regular, daily physical activity can lower the risk of heart disease. Physical activity helps control your weight. It also reduces the chances of developing other conditions that may put a strain on the heart, such as high blood pressure, high cholesterol and type 2 diabetes.

If you haven\t been active for a while, you may need to slowly work your way up to these goals, but in general, you should do aim for at least:

150 minutes a week of moderate aerobic exercise, such as walking at a brisk pace
75 minutes a week of vigorous aerobic activity, such as running
Two or more strength training sessions a week
Even shorter bouts of activity offer heart benefits, so if you can\t meet those guidelines, don\t give up. Just five minutes of moving can help, and activities such as gardening, housekeeping, taking the stairs and walking the dog all count toward your total. You don\t have to exercise strenuously to achieve benefits, but you can see bigger benefits by increasing the intensity, duration and frequency of your workouts.
    </string>
    <string name="tip8">
        <b>3.EAT HEART-HEALTHY DIET</b> - A healthy diet can help protect the heart, improve blood pressure and cholesterol, and reduce the risk of type 2 diabetes. A heart-healthy eating plan includes:

Vegetables and fruits
Beans or other legumes
Lean meats and fish
Low-fat or fat-free dairy foods
Whole grains
Healthy fats, such as olive oil
Two examples of heart-healthy food plans include the Dietary Approaches to Stop Hypertension (DASH) eating plan and the Mediterranean diet.

Limit intake of the following:

Salt
Sugar
Processed carbohydrates
Alcohol
Saturated fat (found in red meat and full-fat dairy products) and trans fat (found in fried fast food, chips, baked goods)
    </string>
    <string name="tip9">
<b>4.MAINTAIN HEALTHY WEIGHT</b> - Being overweight — especially around the middle of the body — increases the risk of heart disease. Excess weight can lead to conditions that increase the chances of developing heart disease — including high blood pressure, high cholesterol and type 2 diabetes.

The body mass index (BMI) uses height and weight to determine whether a person is overweight or obese. A BMI of 25 or higher is considered overweight and is generally associated with higher cholesterol, higher blood pressure, and an increased risk of heart disease and stroke.

Waist circumference also can be a useful tool to measure how much belly fat you have. The risk of heart disease is higher if the waist measurement is greater than:

40 inches (101.6 centimeters, or cm) for men
35 inches (88.9 cm) for women
Even a small weight loss can be beneficial. Reducing weight by just 3% to 5% can help decrease certain fats in the blood (triglycerides), lower blood sugar (glucose) and reduce the risk of type 2 diabetes. Losing even more helps lower blood pressure and blood cholesterol level.
    </string>
    <string name="tip10">
        <b>5. GET GOOD QUALITY SLEEPS</b> - People who don\t get enough sleep have a higher risk of obesity, high blood pressure, heart attack, diabetes and depression.

Most adults need at least seven hours of sleep each night. Make sleep a priority in your life. Set a sleep schedule and stick to it by going to bed and waking up at the same times each day. Keep your bedroom dark and quiet, so it\s easier to sleep.

If you feel like you\ve been getting enough sleep but you\re still tired throughout the day, ask your health care provider if you need to be evaluated for obstructive sleep apnea, a condition that can increase your risk of heart disease. Signs of obstructive sleep apnea include loud snoring, stopping breathing for short times during sleep and waking up gasping for air. Treatments for obstructive sleep apnea may include losing weight if you\re overweight or using a continuous positive airway pressure (CPAP) device that keeps your airway open while you sleep.
    </string>
    <string name="tip11">
        <b>1.CONTROLLING HIGH BLOOD PRESSURE</b> (hypertension) - This is one of the most important things you can do to reduce your stroke risk. If you\ve had a stroke, lowering your blood pressure can help prevent a subsequent TIA or stroke. Healthy lifestyle changes and medications are often used to treat high blood pressure.
    </string>
    <string name="tip12">
        <b>2.LOWERING THE AMOUNT OF CHOLESTEROL AND SATURATED FAT IN YOUR DIET</b> - Eating less cholesterol and fat, especially saturated fat and trans fats, may reduce buildup in the arteries. If you cant control your cholesterol through dietary changes alone, your doctor may prescribe a cholesterol-lowering medication.
    </string>
    <string name="tip13">
        <b>3.DRINKING ALCOHOL IN MODERATION, IF AT ALL</b> - Heavy alcohol consumption increases the risk of high blood pressure, ischemic strokes and hemorrhagic strokes. Alcohol may also interact with other drugs you are taking. However, drinking small to moderate amounts of alcohol, such as one drink a day, may help prevent ischemic stroke and decrease the bloods clotting tendency. Talk to your doctor about whats appropriate for you.
    </string>
    <string name="tip14">
        <b>4. AVOIDING ILLEGAL DRUGS</b> - Certain street drugs, such as cocaine and methamphetamine, are established risk factors for a TIA (transient ischemic attack) or a stroke.
    </string>
    <string name="tip15">
        <b>5. MANAGING DIABETES</b> - Diet, exercise and losing weight can help you keep your blood sugar in a healthy range. If lifestyle factors don not seem to be enough to control your diabetes, your doctor may prescribe diabetes medication.
    </string>
<string name="tip16">
    <b>1. DO NOT SMOKE</b> - If you have never smoked, do not start. Talk to your children about not smoking so that they can understand how to avoid this major risk factor for lung cancer. Begin conversations about the dangers of smoking with your children early so that they know how to react to peer pressure.
</string>
    <string name="tip17">
        <b>2. STOP SMOKING</b> - Stop smoking now. Quitting reduces your risk of lung cancer, even if you have smoked for years. Talk to your doctor about strategies and stop-smoking aids that can help you quit. Options include nicotine replacement products, medications and support groups.
</string>
    <string name="tip18">
        <b>3. AVOID SECONDHAND SMOKE</b> - If you live or work with a smoker, urge him or her to quit. At the very least, ask him or her to smoke outside. Avoid areas where people smoke, such as bars and restaurants, and seek out smoke-free options.
</string>
    <string name="tip19">
        <b>4. AVOID CARCINOGEN AT WORK</b> -  Take precautions to protect yourself from exposure to toxic chemicals at work. Follow your employers precautions. For instance, if you are given a face mask for protection, always wear it. Ask your doctor what more you can do to protect yourself at work. Your risk of lung damage from workplace carcinogens increases if you smoke.
</string>
    <string name="tip20">
        <b>5. EXERCISE MOST DAYS OF THE WEEK</b> - If you do not exercise regularly, start out slowly. Try to exercise most days of the week.
</string>
     <string name="link">
         <b>LINK TO THIS TIPS:</b>
         https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/type-2-diabetes/in-depth/diabetes-prevention/art-20047639
     </string>

    <string name="link2">
        <b>LINK TO THIS ARTICLE:</b>
         https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/diabetes/symptoms-causes/syc-20371444
     </string>

    <string name="link3">
        <b>LINK TO THIS ARTICLE:</b>
        https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/heart-attack/symptoms-causes/syc-20373106
     </string>
    <string name="link4">
        <b>LINK TO THIS TIPS:</b>
       https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/heart-disease/in-depth/heart-disease-prevention/art-20046502z
     </string>
    <string name="link5">
         <b>LINK TO THIS ARTICLE:</b>
        https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/stroke/symptoms-causes/syc-20350113
    </string>
    <string name="link6">
        <b>LINK TO THIS TIPS:</b>
      https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/stroke/symptoms-causes/syc-20350113
    </string>
    <string name="link7">
         <b>LINK TO THIS ARTICLE:</b>
      https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/lung-cancer/symptoms-causes/syc-20374620
    </string>
    <string name="link8">
         <b>LINK TO THIS TIPS:</b>
     https://www.mayoclinic.org/diseases-conditions/lung-cancer/symptoms-causes/syc-20374620
    </string>



     <string name="link9">
          New drugs for the treatment of migraines
         <a href = "https://www.drugs.com/medical-answers/new-drugs-treatment-prevention-migraine-3515053/?fbclid=IwAR0BEB5bVxRVrLh56n5Nu8XjWP0OwBl6ruOFwvQOn_9LKO5OVesuByjIMp8">
             view here
         </a>
     </string>

    <string name="link10">
        Second Alzheimer’s drug to slow disease’s progression may be approved in the US this year
         <a href = "https://edition.cnn.com/2023/07/17/health/second-alzheimers-drug-to-slow-disease-may-be-approved-this-year/index.html">
             view here
         </a>
     </string>

    <string name="link11">
         Scientists may have found the missing link between heart disease and sleep problems
         <a href = "https://www.livescience.com/health/heart-circulation/scientists-may-have-found-the-missing-link-between-heart-disease-and-sleep-problems">
         view here
         </a>
     </string>



</resources>